Gabriel Lévesque-Duval

273 Emmanuel-Fougerat Laval, QC, H7L 5H5 514-654-4420

glevesqueduval@gmail.com

Languages: French and English

Creative, communicative, and efficient developer determined to help people by creating useful software. Excellent time management by following the agile development frameworks learned during 3 internships and one year of managing a software team of 15 people.

Skills

- TypeScript, React, React Native
- C#, .NET
- Docker

- SQL, GraphL
- Java, Kotlin
- Kubernetes

Experience

Software engineering internship

May 2023 - September 2023

Expedia Group, Montréal

- Developed Spring backend services leveraging AI models to deliver relevant destinations images
- Deployed services to Kubernetes clusters
- Created a React web application to manage the services configurations
- Built a tool that automatically exports UAT run results to Elasticsearch, triggered by GitHub Actions

Web and mobile development internship

May 2022 – September 2022

Ora Médical, Montréal

- Developed a Next.js web application from scratch to monitor patient data
- Implemented a complete UI redesign in React Native for the company's mobile app
- Made use of Realm to store and sync the mobile app's offline data with the server
- Used Bit.dev to share and reuse components between the web and mobile app

Full-stack development internship

January 2021 – April 2021

CAE, Montréal

- Created a PHP search engine application that utilizes a NLP model to prevent duplicate Jira issues by intelligently detecting similar tickets
- Designed and implemented a .NET API to store and share files using a SQL database
- Coded a customizable and reusable React form component that was added to my team's Storybook

Web developer

January 2020 - August 2020

Mediavore, Laval

- Created a client-friendly bug reporting tool that allows users to select and comment on HTML elements directly within their website using JavaScript and jQuery
- Maintain websites of 200 different clients
- Developed a PHP application to manage the company's clients' information internally

Education

Exchange semester in software engineering

Since fall 2023

Technical University of Munich

Bachelor's in software engineering (GPA 4.0/4.3)

Since fall 2020

École de technologie supérieure

Technical program in computer Science

2020

Collège Montmorency

Student club

Software team leader

Club Capra, Montréal

- Program a mobile robotics platform in Python and C++
- Program a telemetry web user interface using React and Electron
- Task and project management for a team of 15 people
- Competed at Robocup 2022 in Bangkok
- Won the Best in Class in Search & Rescue award at EnRicH 2023 in Austria

•

Scholarships

- 1 000\$ Scholarship of excellence from the Foundation of Collège Montmorency
- Entry scholarship of 2 500\$ at École de technologie supérieure